Kevin A. Howell

kevin@kahowell.net (276) 206-9153 http://www.kahowell.net

SUMMARY

Open-source software engineer specializing in DevOps, Java, and Python.

SKILLS

Experience in Java, Python, and Groovy

7+ years of professional experience in Java EE development

3+ years of professional experience in Python development

Experience in configuration management and system orchestration using Puppet and Ansible

Experience in enterprise integration with Camel and ActiveMQ

Experience in development of C-I/C-D pipelines in Jenkins

Experience in Maven and Git

Experience in and a strong preference for Linux, including CLI

Experience in agile software development

Comfortable in unfamiliar territory; ability to adapt quickly to unfamiliar concepts/situations

Strategic thinker

EXPERIENCE

Red Hat - Candlepin (Raleigh, NC)

Senior Software Engineer - October 2017 - present

Software Engineer - August 2016 - October 2017

- Participated in the Candlepin, subscription-manager, and virt-who open source software projects.
- Participated in releases of Red Hat Enterprise Linux and Red Hat Satellite 6.
- Worked in a variety of programming languages including Python, Java, Ruby, and C.
- Improved build, release, and process automation.
- As lead for subscription-manager, drove development of subscription-manager.
- As tech lead, organized work for the team, facilitated team discussions, and represented the team to stakeholders.

Red Hat IT - SOA Services & ESB (Raleigh, NC)

Senior Software Applications Engineer - February 2016 - August 2016

Software Applications Engineer - May 2014 - February 2016

- Worked closely with DBAs to migrate mongodb configuration off of custom Puppet code and onto the upstream PuppetLabs mongo module.
- Drove the specification of standards for RESTful services for IT (https://github.com/lightblue-platform/lightblue-docs-specs/pull/43).
- Represented SSE in project meetings.
- Provided production support for business critical services and integrations.
- Ported legacy and developed new enterprise integration logic with JBoss Fuse (Camel) and JBoss A-MQ (ActiveMQ).
- Developed and maintained RESTful and SOAP-based SOA services.
- Automated deployment and configuration of new applications using Puppet.
- Led development of C-I/C-D pipelines in Jenkins.
- Worked closely with operations to implement Ansible for release and operations tasks.

TekSystems/Red Hat IT - SOA Services & ESB (Raleigh, NC)

Software Applications Engineer (Contract Position) - November 2013 - May 2014

• (See above)

CGI Federal (Fairfax, VA/Durham, NC)

Consultant - August 2011 - November 2013

- Designed and developed Java EE webapps used by EPA to collect chemical information from the chemical industry (utilizing Stripes Framework, Hibernate, Spring, JAXB, and jQuery).
- Designed and developed utilities to sanitize, transform, and report on collected chemical data.
- Wrote shared jQuery plugins for UI components.
- Designed and developed custom ETL solutions, with various source and target databases including Oracle, Documentum (DFC), and MS Access.
- Developed custom data parsers in Python and Groovy (for CSV files and XML with rapidly changing schemas, respectively).

College of William & Mary - Department of Computer Science (Williamsburg, VA) Lab Consultant - $\bf Spring\ 2010$ - $\bf Spring\ 2011$

- Tutored students in fundamental course topics such as object-oriented programming and data structures.
- Debugged students' Java and Python code.

Fifes and Drums of Yorktown (http://www.fifes-and-drums.org) (Yorktown, VA) Webmaster - December 2009 - present

- Redesigned the site; migrated old content to the new layout.
- Wrote a photo gallery script which generates photo galleries from uploaded directories of pictures.
- Developed an event participation tracking system (online promise sheet).
- Utilized PHP, MySQL, HTML, and CSS.

SELECTED OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS

xform-live (Java)

Webapp to enable preview of XSLT transformations, enabling developers to easily preview effects of changes to XSLT code.

https://github.com/kahowell/xform-live

sdl2-cffi (python)

Python CFFI wrapper for SDL2, which is a cross-platform game development library. Generated by parsing the SDL2 headers.

https://github.com/kahowell/sdl2-cffi

More at https://github.com/kahowell

CERTIFICATIONS

- Red Hat Certified Architect (RHCA) 150-059-160
- Red Hat Certificate in Deployment and Systems Management 150-059-160
- Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Administration 150-059-160
- Red Hat Certified Specialist in Configuration Management 150-059-160
- Red Hat Certified Specialist in Containerized Application Development 150-059-160
- Red Hat Certified Specialist in Ansible Automation 150-059-160
- Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE) 150-059-160
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) 150-059-160

EDUCATION

College of William & Mary, Williamsburg, VA Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, May 2011 Minor in Mathematics